http://www.guilford.com/privacy-policy

Home » Privacy Policy
Interested in the California Consumer Privacy Act? Please see our information for California users.
Guilford Press is a publisher of books, periodicals, and DVDs. We pride ourselves on working with recognized experts in their respective fields to translate specialized knowledge into valuable resources, which we make available to the general public, clinicians, academics, and researchers. Our websites (https://www.guilford.com and https://guilfordjournals.com) are the primary tools through which we connect our customers to these resources.
Guilford takes your online privacy and security very seriously. We’ve designed this site to be nonintrusive while offering the full functionality you expect. This Privacy Policy sets out how Guilford treats personal data, including the personal data collected or processed through this website, and our Cookie Policy page explains how and why our website uses cookies. Guilford is the controller of this personal data and is responsible for your information.
We need to collect and process personal data in order to run our business. By using our websites, you confirm that you consent to us using your information in the ways we describe. If you have any questions about this privacy policy or how we handle personal data, please contact us at info@guilford.com or by using the contact information below.
What Personal Information Do We Gather and Why?
The information we gather from customers allows us to run our business. For example, it allows us to enable purchases and process orders, grant permissions requests, renew subscriptions, administer and improve our website, and help customers identify titles of potential interest from our catalog.
Information You Provide
We receive and store the information you supply to us when you create an account, place an order with us, sign up for services such as e-alerts, and when you communicate with us by telephone, email, or social media. This information includes your login and password, which enables us to ensure that you can securely use our site. However, your password is encrypted before it is recorded to disk, so we cannot read or access it; only you know your password on our website. Other information you provide may include your contact and shipping information, such as your name, delivery address, telephone number, and email address. We receive credit card numbers in order to process online purchases, but as an additional security precaution we do not store these numbers.
We also receive and store the information you provide when you make requests such as a permission request for the use of copyrighted materials or a request for a free copy of a book for potential course adoption.
Guilford may receive information about a person who is not a Guilford customer or account holder (a “third party”) in certain circumstances. For example, we may receive contact and shipping information for a third party if you send them one of our products through our website. A third party can contact Guilford support at any time if they do not want us to retain their information.
At times, Guilford offers special discounts to students who purchase our materials. In order to confirm the validity of these purchases, we may request a student ID number so we can verify your student status. We also enable disabled students to request electronic texts of our materials; however, we do not process these requests through our website, we only do so via mail, fax, or email.
Automatic Information
We also collect certain information automatically. Like many websites, we use cookies and we obtain certain types of information when your web browser accesses guilford.com or guilfordjournals.com. Cookies are used to enable online ordering and access to supplementary materials, to keep track of your display preferences, and for site analytics. We do not use or permit any tracking or advertising cookies on our site. You can learn more about how we use cookies in our Cookie Policy.
We also collect aggregate usage data for our website, which includes browsing patterns, the Internet Protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, computer and connection information such as browser type, version, and time zone setting, browser plug-in type and version, and operating system and platform, to enable us to understand how our website is being used and to develop and refine it to better serve our customers. We may also aggregate usage and purchase information across customers to enable particular features.
At times we may use software tools such as JavaScript to measure and collect session information, including page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information (such as scrolling, clicks, and mouse-overs), and methods used to browse away from the page, in order to improve the relevancy and responsiveness of our site.
Our Legal Bases for Processing Personal Information
We rely on three separate but overlapping bases to lawfully obtain and process your personal information. First, where you have given us valid consent to use your data in certain ways, we rely on your consent.
Second, as described in more detail below, in certain cases we may process your information where this is necessary to further legitimate interests, such as compliance with the law or fraud prevention, so long as those legitimate interests are not overridden by your rights or interests.
Third, in some instances we process your personal information in accordance with a contract between you and us, such as the Terms and Conditions of Use of Online Journals.
How and When Do We Share Information?
As set out below, Guilford only shares information on a limited basis in order to process orders, ship products, and run our business.
Service Providers:
We employ other organizations to perform certain functions on our behalf. This includes: delivering packages, processing credit card payments, analyzing data, providing marketing or customer service assistance, delivering online journal content. These third parties have only limited access to your information, may use your information only to perform these tasks on our behalf, and are obligated to Guilford not to disclose or use your information for other purposes. If you have any questions about the specific service providers we currently use, please contact us using the contact information below.
Legitimate Interests / Protection of the Public and Our Business:
We will release personal and account information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet legitimate national security or law enforcement requirements; to protect, establish, or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims, including to collect a debt; to comply with a subpoena, court order, legal process, or other legal requirement; or when we believe in good faith that such disclosure is necessary to comply with the law, prevent imminent physical harm or financial loss, or investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal activities, suspected fraud, threats to our property, or violations of our Terms and Conditions.
In limited circumstances, we may also exchange certain information with other companies and organizations for the specific purpose of fraud protection.
Data Transfers
Guilford is based in the United States but makes its products available around the world. The United States, Canada, Member States of the European Economic Area (“EEA”), and other countries are governed by different laws. When your data is moved from your home country to another country, the laws and rules that protect your personal information in the country to which your information is transferred may be different from those in the country where you reside. For example, the legal requirements for law enforcement to gain access to personal information may vary between countries. If your personal data is in the United States, it may be accessed by government authorities in accordance with American law.
Guilford’s websites provide a voluntary service and you can choose whether or not you wish to use them. Because we offer our services to people in countries around the world and use technical infrastructure based in the United States, we need to transfer your personal information to the United States in order to deliver our services. When you sign up for an account to use our services, we ask for your consent to the transfer of your personal data abroad, including to the United States, so that we can process your information and provide our services in accordance with this policy.
How Secure Is Your Information?
Our entire website, including any pages on which you provide us with personal information, is encrypted using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software that encrypts the information passed between our website and your computer. We use a domain-verified Digital Certificate and the security of all pages on the site can be confirmed by the padlock symbol and “https://” visible in the address bar.
For order processing, we of course need to obtain and transmit your entire credit card number. However, as an added security precaution, we do not store your credit card information.
Your account is protected by a password that you choose. Your password is encrypted before it is recorded to disk, so we cannot read or access it; only you know your password on our website. It is important for you to protect against the theft or unauthorized access of your login and password. If using a shared computer, please be sure to sign out when you’re finished.
We follow generally accepted industry standards to protect the personal information submitted to us, both during transmission and after it is received. However, no method of transmission or storage is 100% secure.
What Are Your Rights?
If you would like to manage, change, limit, or delete your personal information, you can do so using your Account page, or by contacting us.
Upon request, Guilford will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. In certain cases you have the right to object to the processing of your personal information, to request the deletion of your personal information, and to obtain a copy of your personal information in an easily accessible format. In order to do this, you can contact us at info@guilford.com or use the information listed below under “Contact Us.” We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe and may need to take reasonable steps to confirm your identity before proceeding.
You may withdraw your consent to our processing of your information and the use of our services at any time by emailing us at info@guilford.com to request that your personal information be deleted. If you withdraw your consent to the use or sharing of your personal information for the purposes set out in this policy, we may not be able to provide you with our services. Please note that in certain cases we may continue to process your information after you have withdrawn consent and requested that we delete your information, if we have a legal basis to do so.
Guilford will retain and use your information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your information to comply with applicable tax/revenue laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We may also retain log files for the purpose of internal analysis, for site safety and security, to improve site functionality, or where we are legally required to retain them for longer time periods.
We offer our customers the opportunity to receive information about our company and products that we think may be of interest to them. If you no longer wish to receive such information then we will stop sending it. Any emails that we send contain an obvious means of unsubscribing from further messages, with a link appearing at the bottom of the email. You can also opt out of receiving marketing information at any time by choosing “opt out of email or mail” from your account settings.
As set out above, our website uses cookies to enable some of our key features, like online ordering, signing into your account, and accessing supplementary materials for your purchased items. We therefore recommend that customers leave their cookies turned on. However, the choice of whether to use cookies is yours. Please see our Cookie Policy for more information.
Data Retention
Guilford will retain and use your information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (for example, if we are required to retain your information to comply with applicable tax/revenue laws), resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. We may also retain log files for the purpose of internal analysis, for site safety and security, to improve site functionality, or where we are legally required to retain them for longer time periods.
Guilford will retain your information only for as long as is necessary for the purposes set out in this policy, for as long as your account remains open (i.e., for the lifetime of your account), or as needed to provide you with our services.
If you no longer wish to use our services, you may unsubscribe from postal or email lists, or request that your data be deleted.
California Consumer Privacy Act and Information for CA Customers
The California Consumer Privacy Act of 2018 was signed into law by California Governor Jerry Brown on June 28, 2018 and went into effect on January 1, 2020.
The Act (the full text of which is available here) gives consumers (defined as natural persons who are California residents) four basic rights in relation to their personal information:
To know what personal information is being collected about them.
To know whether their personal information is sold or disclosed and to whom, and to say no to the sale of personal information.
To access their personal information.
To equal service and price, even if they exercise their privacy rights.
Guilford does not sell customer personal information to any third parties. If you would like to manage, request, or delete your personal information, you can do so using your Account page, or by contacting us by mail, email, or phone. You may freely exercise these rights without being denied goods or services by us.
Contact Us
If you have any questions, comments or suggestions about how we handle personal information you can contact Guilford support by telephone at (800) 365-7006, ext. 1, or by sending an email to info@guilford.com. You can also write to us at the following address:
Guilford Press - Privacy Policy
370 Seventh Avenue
Suite 1200
New York, NY 10001-1020
Last Updated: May, 2018
Connect
Your Account
About Us
Copyright © 1997-2020Guilford Press
Don't want the mobile site? Switch to the full site.
X
Save 25% + Free Shipping on Online Orders!
Save 25%:
Applies only to prepaid online orders from US and Canadian customers.
Discount is applied to the list price.
You can take advantage of special offers along with the 25% discount by entering a promotional code in the shopping cart. You will receive the larger discount available for each item.
You may return Guilford books (undamaged) within 30 days of receipt for a full refund.
Not applicable to journal renewals.
Free Shipping:
Applies only to prepaid online orders from US customers.
Packages sent via USPS Media Mail. You may choose to pay for rush shipping instead.
We've also reduced shipping charges to Canada to a flat $9.00 per order. Packages sent via CanPar.
From:
To:
Subject:
Your Message:
Add a Note: (Optional)
SendSending...
